L. C. Dunn Papers ca.1920-1974 Mss.B.D917
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, ca.1920-1974 (Box 1)
  - New York Zoological Society (Box 23)
    Blatchley, Myrtice A.
    Ryan, MacGregor
  - Norske Videnskaps-Adakemi, Oslo (Box 23)
  - Norton, W.W. (Box 23)
  - Oehlkers, Friedrich, 1938-1939; 39 items (Box 23)
    Babcock, E.B.
    Beale, J.M.
    Butler, N.M.
    Drury, Betty
    Duggan, S.P.
    Fackenthal, F.D.
    Hanson, F.B.
    Leebrick, K.C.
    Pappenheimer, A.M.
    Pollock, F.
    Ruskins, C.L.
    Sanders, Gerhard
    Sinnott
    US Dept. of Labor, Immigration...
    Wolf, Ernst
    Youngberg, F.
    Displaced German scholars
  - Ogura, Y. (Box 23)
  - Ohno, Susumu (Box 23)
  - Olby, Robert C. (Box 23)
  - Onslow, H. (Box 23)
  - Oral History Records (Box 23)
    Benison, Saul
  - Orel, V. (Box 23)
  - Osborn, Fredrick (Box 23)
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield (Box 23)
  - Osborn, Herbert (Box 23)
  - Ossietzky, Carl von (Box 23)
  - Padoa, Emanuele (Box 23)
  - Pai, Kao Ling (Box 23)
  - Pamphlets (Box 23)
  - Pappenheimer, Alwin M. (Box 23)
    Prentice, E. Parmslee
    Slate, W.L., Jr.
  - Parkes, A.S. (Box 23)
  - Parkhurst, R.T. (Box 23)
  - Parshley, H.M. (Box 23)
  - Patau, Klaus (Box 23)
  - Pauling, Linus (Box 23)
  - Payne, Fernandus (Box 23)
  - Peters, James A. (Box 23)
  - Pettit, Lincoln (Box 23)
  - Pickard, James N. (Box 23)
  - Pincus, Gregory (Box 23)
  - Pineau, Roger (Box 23)
    in re: Biological Aspects of Race
  - Pittendreigh, Colin (Box 23)
  - Pizarro A., Olga (Box 23)
  - Plate, Ludwig (Box 23)
  - Poems (Box 23)
  - Poliakov, Leon (Box 23)
  - Pollitzer, William S. (Box 23)
  - Popenoe, Paul (Box 23)
    See Human Betterment Fdth
  - Pontecorvo, Guido (Box 23)
    Krout, J.A.
    Lane, W.H. Jr.
    Mulliken, Robert S.
  - Post, Richard (Box 23)
  - Provine, William (Box 23)
    Darlington, C.D.
  - Punnet, R.C., 1920- (Box 23)
  - Quay, Thomas (Box 24)
  - Quelprud, Theodore (Box 24)
  - Quinn, Joseph P. (Box 24)
  - Randall, John H. Jr. (Box 24)
  - Refugees, 1929-1942; 5 folders (Box 24)
    Adam, Walter
    American Scholar
    Kotschnig, Walter M.
    Mirsch, Felice
    Displaced German scholars; Eugenics -- Germany; Political issues; Scientific refugees
  - Riley, William A. (Box 24)
  - Rizki, Md. Tahir Mirza, 1948-1970; 38 items (Box 24)
    Baitsell, Geroge A.
    Bodenstein, Dietrich
    Grewal, A.S.
    Education Dept. Embassy of India
    Education Liason Officer, India
    Forster, Roy P.
    Immigration & Naturalization
    Karachi Univ., Pakistan
    National Institutes of Health
    Scantlebury, Ronald E.
    Sigma Xi
    Stone, Frederick
    US Department of Justice
    Biographical and personal data; Drosophila genetics; Graduate study; Publication; Research support
  - Robertson, Alan (Box 24)
  - Rolleston, Mrs. Alma Howard (Box 24)
    see: Howard, Alma
  - Rome - Jewish Ghetto Families (Box 24)
    (see also: Dunn, L.C. Rome - Jewish Community)
  - RC6ttcher, Fritz (Box 24)
  - Rusk, Malcolm (Box 24)
    Lenz, Fritz
  - Russell, Liane B. (Box 24)
  - Russell, Stewart (Box 24)
  - Russell, W. L. (Box 24)
  - Salvemini, Gaetano (Box 24)
  - Sander, Gerhard (Box 24)
    Huskins, C. Leonard
    Price, David E.
    Stone, Fredrick L.
  - Sax, Karl (Box 24)
  - Schermerhorn, Helen Ives (Box 24)
    Peterson, Godfried
  - Schrader, Franz (Box 24)
  - Schwartz, Jack (Box 24)
    Scientists' Statement on the Hydrogen Bomb
  - Science and the USSR (Box 24)
  - Science Bulletin (Box 24)
    vol. 1
    vol. 1, nos. 5 & 6
  - Science in the USSR, 1944-1952; 91 items (Box 24)
    Political issues; Publication; Russian politics and science -- Lysenko, Trofim Denisovich
  - Science Research Associates, Inc. (Box 24)
  - Science under Socialism (Box 24)
  - Serebrovsky, R. (Box 25)
  - Serebrowsky, A.S. (Box 25)
  - Setterfield, H.E. (Box 25)
  - Shapley, Harlow (Box 25)
  - Shull, A. Franklin (Box 25)
  - Shull, George H. (Box 25)
  - Singleton, W. Ralph (Box 25)
  - Sinnott, Edmund W. (Box 25)
    O'Neill, Ethel M.
    Schrader, Franz
    Sinnott, Mrs. Mabel
  - Slanetz, C.A. (Box 25)
  - Smith, John Maynard (Box 25)
  - Snell, George D., 1939-1972; 34 items (Box 25)
    Bittner, John J.
    Carter, T.C.
    Green, Earl
    Sermonte, Guiseppe
    Biographical and personal data; Mouse genetics -- Nomenclature; Recommendations
  - Snyder, L.H. (Box 25)
  - Sokoloff, Alec (Box 25)
  - Spain, 1937 (Box 25)
    Bradley, Jyman R.
    Brunet, D.
    Castillejo, Carmen
    Chase, Roger
    Efron, David
    Hull, Cordell
    Little, Thomas E.
    Lynd, Robert
    Shipler, Guy Emery
    Weisner, Louis
    Yu, Tsune-Chi
  - Stadler, L.J. (Box 25)
  - Stafford, Jean (Box 25)
  - Starr, Mark (Box 25)
  - Steinberg, Arthur G. (Box 25)
    Cummins, Harold
    Diamond, L.K.
  - Stern, Curt (Box 25)
  - Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 25)
    Slate, William L.
  - Sturtevant, A.H. (Box 25)
  - Sucking, Mrs. Joan (Box 25)
  - (Sweeny) Mrs. Dunn (Box 25)
  - Tan, C. (Box 25)
    US Sec. of State
  - Taylor, C.V. (Box 25)
  - Temkin, Oswei (Box 25)
  - Thigpin, Lorna (Box 25)
    Beard, Mary
    University of Pittsburgh
  - Thompson, Edmund B. (Box 25)
  - Thompson, Laura (Box 25)
  - Tozzer, A.M. (Box 25)
  - Unidentified (Box 25)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Org. (UNESCO), 1950-1952; 78 items (Box 25)
    Race and Society
    Tead, Diana
    Conferences and symposia; Evolution -- Race; Human genetics; Publication
  - USSR Corr. with Geneticists, 1928-1946; 104 items (Box 25)
    1926-1928
    1945-1946
    Biographical and personal data -- Cannon, Walter Bradford; Columbia University; Drosophila genetics; Genetics; Political issues; Poultry genetics; Publication; Requests for reprints; Russian politics and science; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - U.S. Department of State (Box 25)
  - University Federation for Intellectual Freedom, 1937-1939; 3 folders
    Committee activities; Eugenics; Political issues; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1 (Box 25)
      American Committee for Democracy & Freedom
      Finkelstein, M.I.
      Pegram, George
    - Folder 2 (Box 25)
      Benedict, Rugh
      Chalmers, Ruthven S.
      Pierce, Harry
    - Folder 3 (Box 25)
      Andrews, Benjamin R.
      Bradley, Lyman R.
      Camacho, Claire
      Counts, George S.
      Foster, Mrs.
      Lopes, Marina
      Mendenhall, Harold C.
      Onia, Frederico de
      Souza, F. Tude
      Stein, Vera
  - University Society (Box 25)
  - Van Doren, Mark (Box 26)
  - Vavilov, Nicolai (Box 26)
    Singer, Rolf
    USSR Ambassador
    Verdoorn, Fr.
  - Verschuer, O. von (Box 26)
  - Vries, Hugo de (Box 26)
    Bryson, Vernon
  - Waddington, C.H. (Box 26)
  - Wallace, Henry A. (Box 26)
  - Warren, D.C. (Box 26)
  - Warwick, B.L. (Box 26)
  - Waters, Nelson F. (Box 26)
  - Weaver, Thomas (Box 26)
  - Weaver, Warren (Box 26)
  - Webster, Leslie T. (Box 26)
  - Weiling, Franz (Box 26)
  - Weinstein, Alexander (Box 26)
  - Weir, Jack A. (Box 26)
  - Wentworth, Edward N. (Box 26)
  - Westergaard, Morgens (Box 26)
    Johannsen, W.
    Shull, George
  - Weygand, James L. (Box 26)
  - Wheat, Frank M. (Box 26)
  - Wheeler, J.F.G. (Box 26)
  - White, O.E. (Box 26)
  - Whiting, Phineas W., 1920-1940; 28 items (Box 26)
    Conferences and symposia; Genetics -- Habrobracon; Mouse genetics; Poultry genetics; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Whitney, Leon F. (Box 26)
  - Wiggins, Henry H. (Box 26)
  - Wilder, Russell (Box 26)
  - Williams, James D. (Box 26)
  - Williams, L. Pearce (Box 26)
  - Willier, B. (Box 26)
  - Wilson, Edwin B. (Box 26)
  - Winge, O. (Box 26)
  - Wissler, Clark (Box 26)
  - Wistar Institute (Box 26)
  - Wolf, Ernst (Box 26)
  - Woodbridge, Frederick J.E. Memorial Lecture (Box 26)
  - Woolf, Harry (Box 26)
  - World War II Relief (Box 26)
  - Wright, G. Payling (Box 26)
  - Wright, Sewall, 1920-1964; 30 items (Box 26)
    Criticism of Dunn, Genetics...
    Mendel's Ratios
    Displaced German scholars; Genetics; History of biology, especially genetics; Mouse genetics; National Academy of Sciences; Poultry genetics; Publication; Recommendations -- Charles, Donald Randolph; Recommendations -- Jollos, Victor; Recommendations -- Muller, Hermann Joseph; Reviews; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Wu, Tai Te (Box 26)
    Apgar, Virginia
    Crick, F.H.C.
    Donohue, Jerry
    Pauling, Linus
    Wilson, Herbert R.
  - Yanagisawa, Kaichiro, 1962-1973; 4 folders (Box 26)
    The Mechanism of Abnormal Transmission Ratios at I Locus in the House Mouse
    Olive, Lindsay
    Sperm Nucrographs
    Mouse genetics; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Yarborough, Senator Ralph (Box 26)
  - Yerkes, Robert M. (Box 26)
  - Zamenhof, Stephen (Box 26)
  - Zawadowsky, M.M. (Box 26)
  - Zhebrak, A.R. (Box 26)
  - Zirkle, Conway (Box 26)
  - Zlotowski, Ignace (Box 26)
  - Zulueta, Antonio De (Box 26)
- Series II. Oral history interview transcripts, 1958-1960; 2 boxes; 1.0 linear foot
  Between 1958 and 1960, Dunn was interviewed by Saul Benison as part of the oral history project conducted by Columbia University. The series contains eight bound volumes of unedited typed transcripts with manuscript annotations (by Dunn). The originals are housed at Columbia University.
  Biographical and personal data; Columbia University; Graduate study; Harvard University -- Castle, William Ernest; Harvard University -- East, Edward Murray; Harvard University -- Wright, Sewall; Mouse genetics; Political issues; Poultry genetics; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Volumes 1-4, 1958-1960 (Box 27)
  - Volumes 5-8, 1958-1960 (Box 28)
- Series III. Reprints, 0.25 linear feet
  - Dunn, L. C.
  - The Roman Jewish Community..., Dunn, Stephen
  - E
  - G - H
  - How Much Can We Boost IQ..., Jensen, Arthur Robert
  - J - K
  - L
  - M
  - O
- Series IV. Genetics editorial correspondence, 1935-1949; 2 boxes; 1 linear foot
  Correspondence regarding the acceptance and publication of manuscripts accrued while Dunn was acting as editor of Genetics. While most of the correspondence is perfunctory and concerned primarily with the editorial details, there is occasional commentary on the work of other geneticists and the value of particular lines of research. Among many other correspondents are A.H. Sturtevant and Barbara McClintock.
  Business; Editorial matters -- Genetics; Publication -- Genetics; Referee's report
  - Correspondence A-Mc, 1935-1949 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence M-Z, 1935-1949 (Box 30)
- Series V. Research, 2 boxes; 1.0 linear foot
  - James Island, South Carolina, 1955-1957; 11 folders
    Human genetics; Population genetics -- African Americans; Population genetics -- Blood groups; Population genetics -- Records; Population genetics -- Sickle cells; Population genetics -- Thalassemia
    - Clinic Population
    - Families, 2 folders
    - Genetics Material
    - Hematology Record Sheets, 3 folders
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders
    - Protocols
    - Thalassemia, Sickle Cell Records
  - Rome Jewish Community, 1953-1968; 30 folders; Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974
    Anti, Carlo
    Canaperia, Giovanni A.
    Citone, Angelo
    D'Ancona, Umberto
    Fajrajzen, Stefano
    Figa-Talamanca, Mario
    Ford Foundation
    Gini, Corrado
    Gurevitch, J.
    Levi, Giuseppe
    Livi, Livio
    Luria, S.E.
    Mourant, Arthur E.
    Orr, Boyd
    Ravenna, Signora
    Roth, Cecil
    Sachs, Leo
    Sanghvi, L.D.
    Seta, Angiolino B. della
    Sheldon, William
    Talamanca
    Conferences and symposia; Graduate study -- Auerbach, R.; Graduate study -- Pollitzer, William S.; Human genetics; Immunogenetics; Population genetics -- Blood groups; Population genetics -- Rome, Jewish community; Population, demography; Research support; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - The Ancient Jewish Community of Rome, manuscript, Circa 1968; Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974; Dunn, S. P.
    - Blood Groups (see also: Blood Study), Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974
      Dreyfuss, F.
    - Correspondence, 1953
    - Correspondence, 1954
    - Correspondence, 1955-1956, n.d.
    - Findings, preliminary
    - Gene Frequencies in Families, Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974
    - A Genetical Study of a Jewish Community, the Old Ghetto in Rome, n.d.; Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974
    - The Jewish Community of Rome, Scientific American, March 1957; Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974; Dunn, S. P.
    - Man in the City (Symposium Lecture), 1968
    - Notebook, contacts
    - Notes
    - Population Statistics, Italy
    - Population Statistics, Jewish Community
    - Protocol Tables, n.d.
    - Protocol Tables, Distribution of Individuals
    - Research Data, 11 folders
    - Research, other scholars
    - Research Participants, Family Cards, n.d.
    - Research Participants, Notebook (Alphabetical), n.d.
    - Research Participants, Notebook (Numerical), n.d.
    - Travel Document and Records, 1953-1954
- Series VI. Photographs, 1911-1974; 1 box; 0.5 linear feet
  Miscellaneous photographs, primarily personal, of Dunn, his family and colleagues. Along with a small number of personal photos of Dunn from his childhood through old age, there are two outstanding photo albums. The first of these was kept by Dunn during his days as a student at Dartmouth (1911-1915), and is a fine example of the undergraduate genre, replete with images of cavorting students, football games, the winter carnival, the campus and his friends. There are several images of Dunn dressed as a woman (presumably as a stunt) and other of Dunn's friends in blackface.
  Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Columbia University; Dartmouth College; Photographs
  - Photo album, June 18-July 2, 1941; 1 vol., 37 photos; Cold Spring Harbor Symposium on Quantitative Biology (Box 31)
    Album of informal snapshots taken at the Cold Spring Harbor Symposium and presented to Dunn by K. S. Brehme. Also includes snapshots from the Growth Symposium held at Dartmouth, July, 1941. Among others, the album includes images of:
    Delbruck, Max
    Dunn, L. C.
    Harrison, R. G.
    Huskins, C. L.
    Luria, Salvador
    Mayr, Ernst
    McClintock, Barbara
    Painter, T. S.
    Riddle, Oscar
    Schultz, Jack
    Stadler, L. J.
    Willier, Benjamin H.
  - Staff, 1943; 1 photo; Columbia University. Department of Zoology (Box 31)
    Formal shot of department taken on the fiftieth anniversary of the graduate program at Columbia.
  - Recipients of honorary degrees, 1952; 2 photos; Dartmouth College (Box 31)
    Dunn appears in one photo
  - Photo portraits, 1914-ca.1974; 15 photos; Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974 (Box 31)
    Formal, semi-formal and candid portraits of Dunn and family at various stages of his career, from undergraduate days through retirement.
  - Childhood photos, ca.1895-1909; 13 photos; Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974 (Box 31)
    Includes 4 cabinet cards and one mounted portrait of Dunn as a young boy; five portraits of Dunn at about age 8-10 (one a photobooth strip); and four images of Dunn in high school, including one with a drill team, one in football gear and one with the Putnam A.C. football team.
  - Dartmouth College photo album, part 1, ca.1911-1915; 117 photos; Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974 (Box 31)
    Marvelous disbound undergraduate photo album with views of the College grounds and buildings, athletics (track and football), Dunn and his friends, college highjinks, summer holidays at Lake George. The cover includes a striking watercolor and ink illustration of a devil, a freshman(?) and a young woman with the caption "Leslie C. Dunn, his book," and "Abandon hope, all ye who enter here."
  - Dartmouth College photo album, part 2, ca.1911-1915; 149 photos; Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974 (Box 31)
    Continuation of part 1, including photos of the Winter Carnival, street parades, more vacations, graduation. Also includes a series of images of Dunn dressed as a girl.
  - Wilhelm Johannsen and William Bateson, ca. 1925; F8.12.20; 1.0 Photograph(s); Fergensen, A. C.
    Full length, informal, sitting outside in front of house
  - Professor Hugo de Vries in experimental garden with two village friends., 1929, August; U4.3.22; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length portrait of de Vries seated outside, plants and buildings in background, with a boy on his right and left.
  - Ivan Petrovich Pavlov, standing outside, arms crossed., U5.2.78; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length profile of Pavlov standing outside, arms crossed.
  - Hugo de Vries standing in garden with unidentified man and woman., ca. 1929; U5.2.81; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 length group portrait of de Vries and man and woman, standing in garden.
  - Alfred Russel Wallace sitting in study, n. d.; U5.2.82; 1.0 Photograph(s); Bust length 3/4 profile of Wallace, book case in background.